insurance joining in
parker hi good morning great to have you
in the show thanks for joining et now
uh you know i'm just going through your
earnings there's been a recovery on a
month and month basis as well and you
know by the monthly data july witnessed
an
uptick in premium collections do you see
the trend actually hold our bhargav and
has august also translated well in terms
of premium collections
uh first thank you for having me on your
show and uh good morning to all your
viewers
uh so yeah what we've seen is uh if you
see month on
numbers april may june july we are
seeing uh
a decent improvement uh across months uh
april of course was really slow may you
know was early trying to pick up
uh but june was a positive month for the
industry and for us july was even more
so
looking ahead uh the trend line gives us
some amount of comfort uh having said
that there is uh one bit of worry that
remains that
uh the the the
these these sporadic changes that is
happening in terms of lockdowns in
certain cities at different points in
time
uh that is a cause of concern so our
senses that will be
strongly correlated to what we see with
the virus
and if we finally see some tapering
coming through in the next
few weeks or thereafter then we should
see a good festive season for us
the motor uh you know insurance is a
large piece
so if we see some some stabilization of
this uh pandemic then we'll see a
good uh festive season on the other side
and that was on the on the motor side on
the health there is generally a
you know consistent improvement that we
are seeing
uh there is some amount of uh kind of
flattening of the demand
uh increase that we were seeing uh the
demand is still elevated but we are not
seeing the increases in the rate of
uh you know growth that we were seeing
earlier and that's also probably
understandable because there's some
amount of saturation of
the numbers that we are seeing at the
health side but overall yes the trend
looks positive
good to have you and good to connect
with you it's been a while we've spoken
on air
my my big picture question is the
insurance industry the segment which you
represent general insurance industry has
seen a kagger growth of about 14-15
percent in last 10 years
because of this pandemic crisis could
there any could there be a structural
change there
good connecting with you nikon yeah and
as i said thank you for having me on
your show
uh look uh in terms of the
overall trend line that we see with the
medium to long term you know of course
this year is a discontinuity for every
industry and for us it is continuous
uh and the growth numbers uh you know
obviously will not be in line with what
we've seen in the past
having said that i think general
insurance business will still show uh
you know some amount of growth uh even
if it's a single
growth for the year we will have a quote
which itself is quite remarkable in the
current context
but if i come back to your question on
the more structural changes we
generally believe that there is a huge
runway of growth for this industry
there is uh underpenetration at a level
which is
which even if you compare with let's say
brics nation
uh if you let's say compared with china
our insurance density is almost 110
chinese numbers i'm not even comparing
with the western world so there is a
huge runway of growth
and our sense is that this industry will
continue to grow at least two and a half
times
real gdp growth for the foreseeable
future
okay you have a formidable track record
that data which is out there in the
public domain that a pad growth of more
than 20 percent much better than
industry
but because of this acquisition will
your historical growth numbers get
challenged because in bharti acquisition
well it's going to be dilutive you're
taking some crop insurance
there their opex is very high so
obviously this will be pushing you back
look uh coming to that deal uh you know
there are many factors that we've looked
at when we've
uh you know considered the uh you know
the scheme
uh that we just announced over the
weekend uh
in terms of our numbers uh obviously i
can't
give you any uh forward looking
statement but if you look at our
10 12 year history and even a period
where
because of deterification the prices
dropped tremendously in this period from
2008 onwards
we've had more than twenty percent
cancer in terms of attacks over
this 12 year cycle so there are certain
things that we've kind of focused on in
terms of being disciplined
in terms of being that's building a
sustainable business and that philosophy
doesn't change
now when we look at the the
potential merger of course it's subject
to all regulatory approvals
uh there are a huge amount of synergies
that we see in the two businesses
uh we see a very uh
high level cultural fit and a good
talent base uh you know in the
in in which in our mind is a very
important factor that
at times doesn't get considered in the
numbers
when you look at integration and overall
high quality uh governance uh even and
a reputation of the of the partners you
know the investors
so all of these factors went into play
when we looked at this transaction now
if you look at the synergies there is of
course release energy in terms of the
distribution
outreach that we get in terms of cost
synergy if you look at
uh you know bharti access there are
slightly smaller in size right and there
is a certain scale
uh disadvantages that you have at that
size and if you look at their operating
cost the expense ratio as we
call it uh that's about 42 while
for us it is in the 20s you know maybe
26 27
depending upon which you look at so
there is a huge amount of cost energy
that we believe you will see
on top of the revenue synergy that i
talked about
that you will now get back into crop
insurance something consciously which
you have avoided isn't that going to be
in baggage
look our view on crop insurance was
always
given by the current reinsurance terms
and the pricing in the market
fundamentally and philosophically we
like the crop insurance business because
the way the scheme was designed we
always believed it was
probably the best architected scheme
that we've seen over the last
you know at least 20 years that we've
been in business and we've been doing
crop insurance
from 2009 onwards so you know
and these discontinuities also can
change some of those dynamics
and if let's say the underwriting model
your rather the
you know the pricing in the market
changes which we are beginning to see
some improvement
and if the insurance uh you know market
changes then it could become a viable
business again for us
it was as i said a call taken given the
current reality of the crop insurance at
that point in time
now in this situation the you know party
access has some
commitment three year commitments in
terms of uh
crop insurance that they've written we
will obviously honor that thereafter we
will study you know in terms of the
uh the quality of business
and the market dynamics at that point in
time and if we believe that it makes
sense for
uh both our policyholder and our
shareholders to continue we will
continue
just when your cd ratio was nearing 100
percent
and you were about to take a giant leap
forward
will the pandemic push all those ratios
down i mean can we assume that whatever
plans you had for fy21 because of corona
everything will be implemented but it's
like everything is got delayed by three
to four quarters is my broad assessment
right on other ratios like combined
ratio i mean cd ratio and other things
look i can't give you a forward looking
statement and combined ratio but just to
give you a sense that where we are and
what we've been
driving our focus has been in terms of
as i said disciplined
underwriting so the combined ratio stays
around 100
and ultimately deliver a 20 rv and
that's something you've seen us being
able to deliver
since the time we've been listed uh
going ahead that objective doesn't
change
and we remain reasonably confident in
the medium term to be able to continue
to deliver that
performance
sure parker i know you've got to run at
950 but just an extension to the point
that you were making right now
you managed to maintain your market
share at eight and a half percent x crop
uh with the merger now you're going to
be the third largest player which are
the segments you think are going to be
the key growth drivers for you both in
terms of revenues as well as market
share going forward
so if you look at the segmental market
share you know post this merger on a
performance basis uh
one uh you know key segment that we've
been uh
focused on and even marquis has been
very strong in his motor
and our overall market share moves from
10 to 12 percent
on a performance basis now even uh with
the 12
market share it is not as if you know
there is no
head room for growth we continue to
believe that motor will continue to do
well
obviously this this year has been a bit
of a setback on the motorcycle
but in the medium to long term we
believe that segment will continue to
grow
the second segment that we've been
always uh
talking a lot about is the uh is the
health and there
we are particularly for new health
business we are
seeing rapid growth and in the
distribution franchise that we are
uh you know hoping to uh bring in
because of the market
acquisition we believe there's an
opportunity to crowd crosstalk and
upsell some of our
health products and the new health you
know initiatives that we are launching
lastly our focus remains on sme
corporate
and digital peace those two will
continue and
even there parties has built some
initial building talks
in terms of scaling those businesses up
which will be complimentary to us